[ Watch on KissFlix.co ]
[Spring of The Blade]
[Episode 29]
-If you have any complaints... -Chunqing.
You can...
Shut up!
The concubines in the residence
hated Xia Yingying
deeply,
but towards Chunqing,
they were jealous.
And Hu Wenzhuo's eldest brother, as Eunuch Xia's subordinate,
had already begun to investigate this matter.
The result would definitely be disadvantageous to Chunqing.
So,
I made a deal with the Hu family
to let Chunqing leave the Xie Residence.
So,
you forced my mother
to leave the Xie Residence
and your side for a second time
for...
It was for her own good.
It was to protect her.
I thought if she left the Xie family,
this place of trouble,
she would be safe.
But I never expected
that she was already pregnant at that time.
Lord Lu even reminded
that fire is forbidden for 3 days during the Cold Food Festival.
and was afraid you two wouldn't have enough to eat,
so he sent over some wheat cakes.
♫ Wheat seedlings are green ♫
♫ Mugwort is sweet ♫
♫ The Bodhisattva of the Lu family spends the cold days ♫
But since things had come to this,
I had to secretly
-to take care of your life. -It tastes good.
This was the best protection
I could give you.
Mother,
have a bite.
Stop working so tirelessly.
-It's time to find Yunya a father. -Old Madam,
we should go.
Let's go quickly.
Old Madam.
Chunqing
harbored the rebel,
the son of Shen Zhibai,
so her house was burned down by the officials.
She...
She
couldn't...
She couldn't escape.
I originally thought
the three of us
still had plenty of time,
and I would definitely find a chance
to bring you and your mother back.
Even if I could only listen from afar
and see that you were safe,
I would be satisfied.
But I never expected that
outside the alley during the Cold Food Festival
was the last time
we would see each other in this life.
After that fire,
I was sick for 3 days.
Since then,
I became a buddhist and vegetarian.
In the past, I didn't believe in anything.
I only believed in myself,
and only believed in the things that power and tactics
brought me.
But after Chunqing died,
I was afraid.
I was afraid of the karma in the world.
I thought if I devoted myself to chanting sutras,
maybe I could accumulate some trivial merits
in exchange for Chunqing
to not to have such a miserable life
in her next life.
Later,
you followed Granny Chen
and gradually grew up.
Although you lived
a poorer life than in the Xie family,
it was peaceful.
Compared to a cruel grandmother like me,
she is more like your real grandmother.
So,
I tried hard to restrain myself
from disturbing your life.
It was until that day...
Old Madam.
Taoist priest Xin Zhen said
finding a mascot
can eliminate the frequent strange occurrences in the Xie family.
A mascot?
That is just
some tricks of a warlock.
The mascot
and the blood-written poem...
were that girl's scheme?
Yuejian.
Actually, our Xie Residence
has fourth lady
who has been wandering outside.
Go and find
her whereabouts.
Yes.
This Qingyuan...
I know.
That was all
carefully planned by you
to get into the Xie Residence.
Since you wanted to get in,
I helped you.
Everything you went through in the Xie Residence,
I know it all.
That wicked Nanny Rong bullied you.
So I found an excuse
and took her life.
Young Master Li
was sincere to you.
I thought of ways
to facilitate this marriage.
And that Yan Rui,
Lord Yan...
How could I not see
his feelings for you?
Many people in the Xie family
saw you as a thorn in their side.
If
Lord Yan protects you,
it might be a way out.
I harbored
the intention of playing along.
But after you entered the Xie Residence,
I secretly made up my mind.
I would do my best to protect you.
I would never let what happened to your mother
happen to you again.
No one is more heartbroken than me
about your suffering.
But I had no choice.
This was all I could do.
This was all you could do?
If you hadn't insisted that night
on exchanging a daughter for a son,
how would there be
all these subsequent sufferings
and bloodshed?
All of this
started because of you.
What did you do to make up for it?
What you did
was just patching up
your previous mistakes.
You are just deceiving yourself.
Qingyuan,
you don't understand.
You are still young.
[Danyue Pavilion]
Before a woman marries,
she must do her best for her maiden family.
After marriage,
she must do her best for her husband's family.
Since I married into the Xie family,
naturally,
passing down the lineage is the priority.
But women cannot inherit the family business.
This is a rule left by our ancestors.
It's not up to me.
But your surname is not Xie.
Your parents,
daughter,
and your blood relatives—
none of them are surnamed Xie.
The world only knows you as Old Madam Xie,
calling you Old Madam Xie.
While your real name,
Lu Lingshu,
is hidden in the cold bronze mirror,
known to no one.
Those achievements you are so proud of
eventually
all became the title of the Xie Residence.
Is this really what you want?
You are wrong.
When people remember the Xie Residence,
they remember me.
My mind is made up.
I will use my old life
to protect the Xie family
for one last time.
This is my fate,
my destiny.
Before you trade your life
for the Xie family,
have you ever wondered
who exactly
killed my mother?
Wasn't it
because your mother harbored
her friend's orphaned child,
angering the imperial court
and bringing disaster upon herself?
No.
Before the guards arrived,
my mother was already dead.
Before she died,
she wanted to meet you again.
I'll take you downstairs to play tomorrow.
Sure.
I saw there were
a lot of wild pheasants downstairs.
Those are wild ducks.
No matter if they're pheasants or ducks,
let's go downstairs and catch them tomorrow.
Sure.
Let's get a net and catch a bunch.
Who's still up so late?
You little rascal.
You're so naughty.
Run,
go to sleep early.
Be a good boy.
I'll make you lots of yummy food tomorrow.
Okay!
You little rascal.
I'll spank you.
You didn't even cover yourself properly.
Little Loser.
Little Loser?
Lu Lingshu.
What should I call you?
Should I call you
Old Madam,
[I respectfully address this letter to the dressing table of the revered Old Madame Xie. I would not dare presumptuously refer to you as mother.]
or
Mother?
Today I finally realized
you didn't protect me
out of courtesy,
nor was it because I am your daughter-in-law.
It was a mother's
love for her flesh and blood,
and her way to make amends.
But what kind of reason
made it worth doing this?
If you cared about me,
how could you bear to abandon me
and hand me over to that alcoholic, gambling,
notorious beast,
making me call him
father?
I was treated like an animal at his command since childhood.
While still young,
I was reduced to making a living in a theater troupe.
On top of that,
the silver I worked so hard to earn
would be taken away by him immediately.
His creditors harassed me every day.
Even he himself,
more than once when he was drunk,
had filthy thoughts about me.
And you?
You stayed deep within the Xie Residence,
behind countless doors,
just watching me.
Watching me covered in mud
and enduring all kinds of humiliation,
yet never revealing a hint of the truth.
To keep it so watertight,
it must not have been easy for you.
I should have been grateful
for your kindness.
But right now,
how can I not feel hatred?
Yet I can't bring myself to hate all of this.
♪ Waiting for a dream to sink into the depths of the night ♪
The real murderer of my mother
♪ Waiting for rain to wash away the heat burning in my eyes ♪
is your fake son,
♪ Waiting for a few flowers to bloom, then quietly fall ♪
Xie Shu.
♪ Only then do I understand right from wrong, and the bitterness ♪
Xie Shu?
♪ Through the courtyard, pear blossoms flutter like snowflakes in a song ♪
♪ Singing the silence of love and hate ♪
That bastard.
♪ Which moment is hypothetical, and which is a real choice? ♪
How dare he kill Chunqing.
♪ Who is drifting aimlessly in the wind? ♪
How dare he kill my daughter!
♪ I wonder why joy is always so scarce in this world ♪
♪ I wonder, is that tear a loss or a gain? ♪
♪ Two souls trapped on the opposite banks of life and death ♪
[Danyue Pavilion]
♪ May you and I overcome karma's bonds ♪
You bastard!
All this karma
and disaster
were deeply seeded
on the night you replaced your daughter
with a boy.
Since things have come to this,
are you still going to take the blame for Xie Shu?
Can you bear to watch
the murderer who killed your daughter
continue to get away with it
and enjoy a life of luxury?
What did you live
your whole life for?
And what are you dying for?
Wait.
Qingyuan.
Now,
do you hate me?
Can you forgive me?
Can you, for one more time, call me...
Yes.
I hate that you defended
these unfair rules.
You are the root of all these disasters.
But I pity you more.
Because you are the one
who has been trapped in this house
for the longest.
Don't make the same mistake again,
Grandmother.
Mother.
The sun is high
and half the day is already gone.
I
came specially to pay my respects.
Pay your respects?
I'm afraid you're reminding me, this old eyesore,
that it's time to pass on.
Mother, why do you say that?
All my life,
my only thought
has been for you
to enjoy longevity and good health.
Only if you are well,
will the Xie family be well.
Bastard.
I originally thought
you still had some true feelings for Chunqing.
That's why I allowed you to marry her.
But you, despicable man,
took her life with your own hands.
So you knew everything.
That's good too.
Now there are no more secrets
between you and me.
Being completely honest with each other,
this is what a real mother and son should be like.
But she was my daughter,
my own flesh and blood.
That doesn't sound right.
Since childhood, I have listened to your earnest teachings.
That's not what you taught me.
You said that
in the face of the Xie clan,
nothing
matters.
Not family,
not friends,
and not even our own lives.
Why today,
are you suddenly getting sentimental
and acting selfishly?
It's not like you
In the eyes of outsiders,
you, Xie Shu, are a highly filial son.
But deep down,
you hate me to the core.
No way.
How could a son hate his mother?
Of course I am a filial son.
I am the most filial son in the world.
And today,
I will carry out my filial duty to the very end,
Mother.
Don't call me Mother.
Every time you call me that,
I hate you a little more.
Since you were a baby,
I should have seen
that you were born a vicious demon.
Mother,
isn't it a little late for that?
Not at all.
Not late at all.
Arrest him!
Have those disobedient people
been dealt with?
-Yes. -They've been dealt with.
Mother,
this is the ginseng soup
Yuejian made for you.
Yuejian?
Sixth Concubine.
Bastard.
I was planning to go keep Chunqing company anyway.
Yes.
But Mother, you're the one
who raised this bastard.
When it comes down to it,
who really killed Chunqing?
It was you.
It was your Xie family.
It was the ancestors of your Xie family
represented by each of those
golden ancestral tablets
who killed her.
Well said.
Lu...
Ling...
Shu...
I know.
The one who deserves to die most
is me.
It's time for me to go.
Farewell, Mother.
Chunqing.
My biggest regret in this life is
that I never held you properly,
nor did I ever hear you call me
"Mother."
Chunqing,
I'm coming to find you.
Mother.
They are all dead.
Grandmother is dead too.
Yunya.
Shen Run.
So,
people really can spend their whole lives
on an empty fame that doesn't belong to them,
giving up everything,
giving up the ones they love.
At the end, they end up
trapping themselves in a cage,
causing so many tragedies.
Master.
Old Madam's confession
has been sent out.
Please... Please rest assured.
You...
I won't say anything.
I don't know anything!
Do you want
to be the second Hu Wenzhuo?
You don't deserve to be.
That old woman married you to me
just to humiliate me.
She just wanted to tell me
that you and I are the same.
From birth,
no matter how smart,
talented,
hardworking,
or good-looking you are,
no one can change
this wretched fate in your bones.
But
I changed it.
Changed it completely.
The Xie family is mine now.
The Xie family's
century-old foundation is all mine.
[A lifetime of fame and success, yet I never knew the truth.]
[My biological daughter was left away from home and died tragically in a fire.]
This is the minister I trust.
His methods are indeed brilliant.
Xie Shu has inherited the Xie Residence for decades
and greatly benefited from the Xie family's protection.
Now,
he claims not to know his background and origins,
which is truly unconvincing to the public.
Xie Shu is well aware of this.
He sent a confession letter,
betting on Your Majesty to accept
his sincerity in offering his adoptive mother's life as an apology.
It is easy to be a foolish ruler,
and not difficult to be a wise one.
The hardest part is knowing that your subjects
are patronizing to your face
and hypocritical,
but for the sake of the big picture, I have to keep them!
Your Majesty wishes to implement new policies,
and shouldn't be hindered by those of the past.
Lord Ye,
within this deep palace,
to govern a vast empire,
one must rely on people.
To rely on people,
one must turn a blind eye
to their selfish desires,
and tolerate being deceived.
Of course, I could have Xie Shu sliced to pieces,
set things right,
cut off old corruptions,
and immediately implement the new policies.
But Xia's faction has just retreated,
and the court is not yet stable.
Without Xie Shu to balance things out,
the gentry and noble families of Hengtang
would be a sheet of loose sand.
Even I
could do nothing about them.
Your Majesty!
I have to focus on the overall interests.
Although accumulated corruptions exist,
the people can still carry the burden and move forward.
But once the country falls into chaos,
there will be far worse factional disputes and wars.
Implementing new policies
requires slow pushing and enduring,
outlasting one Xie Shu after another.
This matter,
let it end here.
Since Old Madam Xie has apologized with her life,
I will leave the Xie family with their last fig leaf.
Let's leave it at that.
Do you think
you're a phoenix?
You're nothing but a beast kept in a cage.
Someday, when I'm in a good mood,
I'll pluck your feathers,
slice your meat,
and see how you taste.
Did you hear me?
Xie Shu!
Xie Shu.
Xie Shu?
All of you, come out!
The patriarch is here.
The patriarch is right here!
Where are you!
When I catch you,
I'll skin you alive, one by one.
Qingrong!
Donglin!
Don't let me catch you!
Is there anyone alive?
You little brats...
You little brats,
get out here!
Where is everyone?
[Fuyu Pavilion]
[Danyue Pavilion]
[Hanxiang Parlor]
[Huifang Garden]
Master.
Where are you going?
Got you!
Let me ask you,
where did all of them go?
-Master... -Where is Sixth Madam?
Sixth Madam has gone mad.
She was sent to the estate.
I have to leave too.
Master,
my old mother is seriously ill at home.
The kindness you've shown me,
I will always remember.
Hengtang
now belongs to me, Xie Shu, alone.
Donglin, it's ours now!
Donglin... Hey! Dong...
I was about to promote you!
Donglin!
Bastard!
♪ The immortal with green hair ♪
♪ Lazy and flirtatious ♪
♪ Drinking toasts ♪
♪ A furrowed brow betrays her sorrow ♪
Chunqing?
♪ Why keep your heart so guarded against me? ♪
You called my mother's name.
It seems
you still care about her.
Qingyuan.
So beautiful.
Well sung, Qingyuan.
This is your mother's dress.